And welcome back to our final time in Jupyter Lab with traditional machine learning.
주피터 연구소에서 마지막 시간을 보내게 됐습니다 전통적인 머신 러닝이죠
It's almost over.
거의 다 끝났어요
Personally, I find it a lot of fun.
개인적으로는 정말 재미있어요
I hope, I hope it hasn't been too unbearable for you.
너무 견디기 힘들진 않았길 바라요
Uh, it's a great experience to have had, though, and I'm really hoping that you've been playing around
그래도 멋진 경험이었어요 스스로 실험해 보셨길 바라요 기능을
yourself, adding some more features, doing some more experiments, seeing if you can't get more out
추가하고 실험하면서 더 많은 걸 얻을 수 있는지 보세요 get it
This was the last chart we looked at, which was word two vec getting an error of 115 on average.
이게 마지막으로 본 도표인데 단어 2개가 평균 115 오류로 나왔어요
And you may remember that we did better with that with the original Bag of Words NLP model that got
기억하실지 모르겠지만 원래 Wards NLP 모델에선 더 잘했죠 114 113까지
us to, I think 114 113.6 or something.
가능했던 것 같아요 6살쯤요
So, um, what we're now going to do is unveil the last two models.
이제 마지막 모델 두 개를 공개할 거예요
We're going to use support vector regression from Support Vector Machines, uh, which is a fancy schmancy
벡터 머신의 벡터 회귀를 지원할 겁니다 전통적인 머신 러닝
traditional machine learning technique.
기술이죠
When you take your, your, your data points and you try and fit a hyperplane that separates the data
데이터 포인트를 가지고 초고층 행성에 맞춰 데이터를 분리할 때 서포트
using things called support vectors, which are the the vectors with the points that are closest to
벡터라는 것을 이용합니다 초고층 행성에 가장 가까운 지점의
the hyperplane.
벡터죠
This may be nonsense to you, or it may be stuff that you know back to front and that I'm not explaining
여러분에겐 말도 안 되는 얘기일 수도 있고 이미 아는 걸 제가 잘 설명하지 못하는 걸 수도
it well.
있죠
In either case, it doesn't matter.
어느 쪽이든 상관없어요
We're just going to take the library as it is from scikit learn, which is so easy to use.
라이브러리를 스키킷 배우기에서 그대로 가져올 거예요 사용하기 아주 쉽죠
We are using a linear SVR.
선형 SVR을 사용해요
There are other types with different kernels that maybe give better results, but they take ages to
더 나은 결과를 내는 다른 종류의 알갱이들도 있지만 실행하는 데 오래 걸리죠
run.
이건 너무 빨리 돌아가요 너무 빠르죠 그래서 제가 제대로 사용하지 않는다는 생각이
its best.
들어요
Um, but I have already run it and it took about five seconds, but the one I used with a different
이미 실행해봤고 5초 정도 걸렸지만 다른 커널로 사용한 건 밤새
kernel I ran all night and still hadn't finished.
실행했는데도 아직 안 끝났어요
So maybe that's somewhere in the middle that that is something that you may be able to to, to explore.
그 중간쯤인 것 같아요 한번 살펴봐 주세요
But this was the the best that I could do.
하지만 이게 제가 할 수 있는 최선이었어요
Uh, and let's see how it performs.
어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
Are you ready?
준비됐어요?
Put in your bets.
Put it! Put it! 베팅하세요
And now I will run it.
이제 실행할게요
No I won't.
안 그럴게요
Oh, there we go.
저기 있네요
That works.
좋아요
Uh, okay.
네
So lots of yellows, lots of reds, lots of greens.
노랑, 빨강, 초록이 많이 들어갔어요
It's obviously not crushing it, but there's some, uh, looks not terrible.
확실히 으깨지진 않지만 심각해 보이지는 않네요
Let's see how that does when we get to the charts.
Get-Tuck Season 1 닙턱 시즌 1 차트에서는 어떨지 보죠
Well, so, uh, it is a winner so far.
지금까지는 아주 좋아요
112.5.
112살요 5분
It is a hair better than the, uh, the prior winner, which was the bag of words linear regression
이전 우승자보다 머리카락이 더 낫네요 그 사람은 단어 한 자루로 선형 회귀 모델이었어요
You can see visually that there's some good things going on, but obviously it's struggling to estimate,
겉으로 보기에는 좋은 점이 많지만 평균보다 훨씬 높은 점수를
um, much above the average point.
추정하기는 어렵네요
Uh, so you can see that there's some progress, but not tremendous progress.
진전이 있긴 하지만 대단한 진전은 없어요
That is our support vector regression model.
지원 벡터 회귀 모델이에요
And now that brings us to our last one, our last model, which is a random forest regression random
이제 마지막 모델로 넘어가죠 임의 숲 임의 숲 퇴행 임의 숲이에요
A particular technique.
특별한 기술이죠
It's a type of ensemble technique that involves combining lots of smaller models.
작은 모델들을 조합하는 일종의 앙상블 기술이에요
The models that it combines, each of them take a random sample of your data points and a random sample
그게 결합하는 모델은 각각 데이터 포인트와 기능의 무작위 샘플을 취합니다
of your features, which in our case means different chunks of our vectors.
우리 경우엔 벡터의 다른 덩어리를 의미하죠
Uh, and trains many models based on that and then combines all of those models.
그걸 바탕으로 훈련하고 그 모델들을 전부 합쳤어요
In the case of a regression, it takes the average across all of these mini models, and that is called
회귀의 경우 이 미니 모델들의 평균을 취합니다 그걸 임의 숲이라고
a random forest.
하죠
So we will see how that works.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
These are generally known to perform well for all shapes and sizes of datasets.
데이터셋의 형태와 크기에 상관없이 잘 작동한다고 알려져 있죠
And they're they're good in that they don't have a lot of hyper parameters.
하이퍼 매개 변수가 많지 않다는 점에서 좋아요
Hyper parameters is what people call just extra knobs to tweak extra things.
하이퍼 매개변수는 추가적인 것을 수정하기 위한 추가적인 노브라고 부르죠
You have to try lots of different values for.
다양한 가치를 시도해 봐야 해요
Random forests don't have a lot of them.
아무 숲이나 있는 건 아니죠
You just use it as it is and see how it does.
있는 그대로 사용하고 어떻게 되는지 보는 거죠
So we've used it as it is and now we will see how it does.
있는 그대로 사용했으니 어떻게 되는지 보죠
Tester dot test and we pass in random forest processor.
테스터 닷 테스트 무작위 처리기로 통과했어요
And again put in your bets.
다시 한 번 베팅을 걸어요 Put
Uh, do you think the random forest is going to do better or worse?
무작위 숲이 더 잘할까요? 아니면 더 못할까요?
112 is the number to beat.
112가 넘어야 할 숫자죠
Let's see how traditional machine learning performs.
전통적인 머신 러닝은 어떤지 보죠
We see some greens.
녹색도 좀 보이고요
We see some reds, we see some greens.
붉은색도 있고 녹색도 있어요
It takes a little bit slower to to run.
뛰는 건 비트보다 좀 느려요
We're seeing some greens, greens, greens, reds, lots of reds.
녹색과 붉은색이 아주 많이 보여요
But generally there we have it.
하지만 일반적으로 그런 게 있어요
There we have it.
다 됐어요
So random forest for the win.
무작위 숲이 이겼어요
The error is $97.
오류는 97달러예요
It's come in under 100.
10만 달러도 안 돼요
We have a nine handle.
손잡이가 9개예요
We've come in under $100.
100달러도 안 돼요
Our best so far.
지금까지는 최고였죠
34% of the dots are green.
34%가 초록색이에요
Here is our line.
우리 대사예요
Here are the green dots.
여기 초록색 점들이 있고요
It's it's also had a bit of a problem getting predicting above the average but not too bad.
비트를 예상하는 데 문제가 좀 있었지만 그렇게 나쁘진 않았어요
You see how well it did with that guy there.
저 사람 때문에 얼마나 잘 됐는지 보세요
It came in green for the really expensive item.
정말 비싼 제품인데 녹색이네요
Uh, and uh uh, it's generally it's generally fared pretty well I would say certainly are running winner.
그리고 대체로 잘 진행되고 있어요 확실히 우승 후보라고 할 수 있죠
Congratulations to Random Forest.
축하해요, 랜덤 포레스트
Uh, and of course, congratulations to you.
물론 축하할 일이죠
If you've beaten this, you can do things like you can use random forest, but put in not only the vectors
이걸 극복했다면 난수 포레스트 같은 걸 쓸 수 있어요 방금 나온 벡터만 넣는
that we've just come up with, but you can add in features as well.
게 아니라 기능을 추가할 수도 있죠
You can manufacture engineer some features and shove them in as well and use that to try and beat beat
어떤 기능을 만들어 끼워 넣을 수도 있죠 그걸 이용해서 이 기록을 깰 수도 있고요 97보다
this number, get do better than than 97.
더 잘 만들 수도 있죠 get it
Uh, and see how you do have fun with traditional machine learning, because this is going to be the
전통적인 머신 러닝을 어떻게 즐기는지 보죠 LMS를
end of it before we move on to trying out LMS.
시험하기 전에 이게 끝이니까요
But first, a quick wrap up with the slides.
그 전에 슬라이드로 간단히 마무리하죠